Let's see how we read information from a file into Python.
我们来看看如何从文件中读取信息并放入 Python 中
To read from a file,
要读取文件
we first need to open it,
首先需要打开文件
which we can accomplish with the built-in function open.
为此 我们可以使用内置函数 open()
We include a string with the path to
我们在其中包含文件路径字符串
the file along with any optional parameters we want to specify.
以及想要指定的任何可选参数
The open function returns a file object which is
函数 open() 会返回一个文件对象 它是一个 Python 对象
a Python object through which Python interacts with the file itself.
Python 通过该对象与文件本身交互
Here we assigned this file object to the variable f.
在此示例中 我们将这个文件对象赋值给变量 f
This second optional parameter specifies the mode in which we open the file.
第二个可选参数指定打开文件的模式
In this case r, or read only.
现在是 r 模式 即读取模式
We are using this mode since we only want to read from the file.
使用该模式是因为我们只想读取该文件
We don't want to change any of its contents.
我们不希望更改任何内容
This parameter isn't really necessary for us to include here,
但是没必要在这里包含该参数
though, since the mode defaults to read only if unspecified.
因为如果未指定的话 默认模式就是该模式
Once we opened a file and created a file object,
打开文件并创建文件对象后
we can use the read method to access the contents of this file.
我们可以使用方法 read() 访问该文件中的内容
This read method takes the text contained in a file and puts it into a string.
该 read() 方法会接受文件中包含的文本并放入字符串中
Here we assign the string returned from this method into the variable file_data.
在此示例中 我们将该方法返回的字符串赋值给变量 file_data
When we are finished with the file f, we should close it.
当我们处理完文件 f 后 应该关闭它
This will free up any system resources taken up by the file.
这样可以释放该文件占用的任何系统资源
Here's an example that uses this file, some_file.txt.
这个示例使用了文件 some_file.txt
It's important to remember
请务必注意 一旦不再需要打开的文件后
to always close files we have opened once we no longer need them.
始终要关闭这些文件
If we open a lot of files without closing them,
如果我们打开很多文件 但是没有关闭这些文件
we can run out of file handles and we won't be able to open any new files.
我们会耗尽文件句柄 无法再打开新的文件
Exactly how many files you can open before
在耗尽文件句柄之前到底可以打开多少文件
running out of handles will depend on your operating system.
取决于你的操作系统
To convince yourself, you can try running the following script in Python.
为了检验这一点 你可以尝试在 Python 中运行以下脚本
At some point for a large enough number,
到了某个时间点 遇到足够大的数字后
you will receive an error.
你将遇到错误
We can see that at 7164 open files,
可以看出 在打开  7164 个文件后
the system no longer had available resources to open any new files.
系统没有可用资源打开新的文件了
To avoid this, it is always a good idea to close any files you no longer need.
为了避免这种情况 记得始终关闭不再需要的任何文件
Opening a file object is like opening a window to look into a file.
打开文件对象就像打开窗口并查看文件
To be more precise,
更准确地讲
it's a window that's only one character
是一个宽只有一个字符的窗口
wide and it always starts off at the very start of the file.
并且始终从文件的开头开始
This is very different from reading a book or a document,
这与阅读图书或文档完全不同
where you can look at multiple words or even pages at once.
阅读图书或文档时 你可以同时查看多个单词 甚至多页内容
Think instead of the file as a long stream of characters.
可以将文件看做有很多字符的长信息流
The file object can look at just one character at a time and order.
文件对象可以按顺序一次查看一个字符
In addition to reading from a file,
除了读取文件之外
you can also write to a file,
还可以写入文件
in which case you will change the content of the file.
这样的话 你将更改文件的内容
To do so, you must open the file in writing mode.
为此 必须以写入模式打开文件
Be careful, once you open a file in writing mode,
请注意 当你以写入模式打开文件时
anything that it contained previously will be deleted.
之前包含的任何内容都将被删除
If you're interested in adding to an existing file without deleting its content,
如果你想向现有文件中添加内容 但是不删除已有内容
you should use append instead of write.
应该使用 append() 而不是 write()
You can visit the Python documentation for
你可以查看相应的 Python 文档
more information on the different modes in which you can open a file.
详细了解可以在哪些模式下打开文件
Since we're in write mode and I don't want to delete what's in this file,
因为我们处在写入模式下 并且我不想删除文件中的内容
let's use another one.
所以我们使用另一个文件
If the file does not exist,
如果文件不存在
Python will create it for you.
Python 将为你创建一个文件
We can now write to the file like this,
现在我们可以像这样写入该文件
and after we're done we will close it like good citizens.
操作完毕后 我们要做个良好公民 关闭该文件
Here you can see that Python created another file which contains the text "Hello World!"
从这里可以看出 Python 创建了另一个文件 其中包含文本“Hello World!”